# **PAUL ADAMS**

## Technology Leader

9 406 Stafford Close, Franklin, TN 37069-4360

#### **SUMMARY**

Results-oriented, goal-driven technologist with 18+ years of leadership experience in software development and IT infrastructure. Diverse background includes startups to international corporations, consulting, various technology stacks, building and motivating teams, SaaS products, and strategic planning. Strong collaboration, analytical, and communication skills.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Mobile Development Manager

06/2022 - Present

#### Ceridian

 Leads a team of 10 Android and iOS Engineers who add new features to Dayforce Wallet, a finance app that provides employees on-demand access to their earned wages

## Mobile Development Manager

09/2019 - 06/2022

Quore

(2 years, 9 months)

- Led a team of Android and iOS Developers who provided hotel industry software solutions for 85.9K monthly active users
- Employed best practices that assured a 99.9% crash-free architecture and adherence to multiple data privacy regulations
- Promoted personal skill improvement to boost team productivity while ensuring high product quality

#### Senior Mobile Developer

06/2015 - 09/2019

# Contractor

(4 years, 3 months)

- Collaborated with stakeholders and cross-functional teams to devise achievable technology roadmaps for 17 n-tier product initiatives
- · Applied agile software development practices throughout the life-cycle of each project, assuring consistently on-time deliverables
- · Engineered 214 titles among 14 App Store categories
- $\cdot\,$  Designed, developed, and maintained three nonprofit websites

# Information Technology Manager

#### U.S. Army

(16 years, 2 months)

- Coordinated and supervised the employment, operation, management, and maintenance of information technology systems worldwide in mobile and fixed facilities
- $\cdot$  Wrote programs to handle the collection, manipulation, and distribution of data for an array of applications and requirements
- Operated telecommunications systems, including automated networks and a full spectrum of data links and circuits

#### **PROJECTS**

## Mobile App Portfolio

https://adams.io/portfolio.pdf

## **SKILLS**

Agile Leadership · Project Budgets · Analytics · Technical Writing · Swift · Objective-C · Kotlin · Java · Ruby · JavaScript · REST · GraphQL · PostgreSQL · SQLite · AWS · Azure · Firebase · CI/CD · TDD · UI/UX · Biometrics · Machine Learning · Bluetooth LE · Offshore Resourcing · Data Privacy · eAccessibility

## **COURSES**

iOS Development Course
Devmountain, Immersive Cohort 4

IT Specialist Advanced Leader Course

U.S. Army, Honor Graduate

Ranger School U.S. Army

# **EDUCATION**

Graduate Study, Counseling Thomas University

Bachelor's Degree, Psychology Thomas University